Guide to the S. Rae Logan Papers 1897-1971
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
S. Rae Logan Papers
1897-1971
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana—Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 054
Logan, S. Rae (Simon Rae), 1885-1970
7.75 linear feet 16 boxes
S. Rae Logan was a Montana and Illinois progressive educator. The collection provides extensive documentation of Logan's career as an educator in rural Montana schools and in the well-known progressive Skokie School of Winnetka, Illinois. It also documents his lifelong and in-depth interests in progressive education, character and religious education, right-wing extremism and its relationship to academic freedom in both K-12 schools and universities, and taxation and its relationship to education funding.
Biographical Note
Simon Rae Logan was born on April 29, 1885 in Rutherford County, North Carolina. He came with his parents to Montana in 1898 and for a time lived near Stevensville, Montana. He attended the University of Montana--Missoula for one year, but graduated from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill with a B.A. in 1908. From 1909 to 1912, he ranched near Arlee, Montana. He was a manager of Theodore Roosevelt's Bull Moose campaign for Missoula County in 1912. In 1913, he was asked to become school superintendent of District 28, Missoula County, when it included a large area from Pablo to south of Arlee. He was a pioneer in the consolidation of one-room schools into centers that offered schooling through high school. He was also instrumental in the formation of the County and Village Teacher's Association in 1913; the group later became a department of the Montana Teacher's Association. He taught school and was a school administrator in Lake County and was school superitendent in Hardin, Montana, from 1919 to 1926. While there he pioneered methods of individual instruction and conducted short winter courses for adults. During those years he was a member of the Chamber of Commerce, the Executive Board of the Montana Farmer's Union, and the Legislative Committee of the Montana Teacher's Association. He led the fight for a graduated income tax to provide state support for public schools. This measure failed at the time, but gained support in later years.
He then became a school administrator in Winetka, Illinois, in 1926 and remained in that position for 21 years. He believed deeply in citizen responsibility in a democracy, and worked actively to promote democratic citizen education at the junior high school leve. He was active in the Northern Illinois Superintendents' Round Table and headed a committee that studied and reported on conditions in the state's correctional schools. He also taught summer school at the University of Montana, Northwestern University, the University of Nevada, and Brigham Young University. As a longtime member of the Progressive Education Association, he was asked to address the International Education Association meeting in Nice, France.
He retired from school work to homestead at Charlo, Montana, where he raised cattle until he was 80 years old. He received distinguished service awards from the Lower Flathead Schoolmasters' Association and the University of Montana chapter of Phi Delta Kappa.
He was married to Frances Logan; they had five children: Herma Biermann, Eileen Hodges, Katherine Tugendhat, Ernest Logan, and Frank Logan. He died in February 1970. She was later married to Harold Guy Merriam; she died in 1993.
The collection contains biographical materials, correspondence, subject files, speeches and writings, printed materials, materials of the Logan's ranch in St. Ignatius, and photographs. It provides extensive documentation of Logan's career as an educator in rural Montana schools and in the well-known progressive Skokie School of Winnetka, Illinois. It also documents his lifelong and in-depth interests in progressive education, character and religious education, right-wing extremism and its relationship to academic freedom in both K-12 schools and universities, and taxation and its relationship to education funding. His autobiography, begun by him and completed by his wife, Frances, documents his career and beliefs as an agitator for educational and social change. There are materials on the Logan's St. Ignatius, Montana, ranch. Family and professional photographs document his ancestors in North Carolina, educational experiences, and schools in which he worked.
The collection is arranged in seven series:
Series I: Biographical1969-1971, 5 folders
Series II: Correspondence, 1906-1970, 2.23 linear feet
Series III: Subject, 1926-1949, 2.5 linear feet
Series IV: Speeches and Writings, 1923-1968, 1 linear foot
Series V: Printed Materials and Scrapbooks, 1913-1970, 1.75 linear feet
Series VI: Logan Ranch, 1931-1948, 0.25 linear feet
Series VII: Photographs, 1897-1968, 0.5 linear feet
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana--Missoula.
The papers remained in the possession of Logan's wife until they were donated to the Archives.
Gift of Frances Logan, 1973 and 1981.
Photographs of Logan's classmates at the University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, were separated and transferred to the North Carolina Collection at the University of North Carolina Library, Chapel Hill.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
University of Montana--Missoula--Students
Academic freedom--United States; Education--United States --Finance; Education, Rural -- Montana; Educational change; Moral education; Progressive education -- Illinois--Winnetka; Progressive education -- Montana; Public schools--Illinois --Winnetka; Public schools--Montana --Hardin; Public schools--Montana --Saint Ignatius; Ranches--Montana--Saint Ignatius; Religious education; Right-wing extremists -- United States; Rural schools -- Montana; School taxes -- Montana
Autobiographies; Personal papers; Photographs; Speeches, addresses, etc., American
Montana; Elementary and Secondary Education
Ranchers--Montana -- Saint Ignatius; School superintendents --Montana
- Biographical, 1969-1971; Series I; 5 folders
  This series contains biographical information about S. Rae Logan and detailed genealogical information about his ancestors. There are notes on family photographs now located in Series VI.
  - Index to articles by and about S. Rae Logan, Skokie, and Winnetka schools, undated (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Logan family history, undated (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Logan family history, notes on photographs, undated (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Biographical, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Obituary and memorial service, 1970 (Box-folder 1/5)
- Correspondence, 1906-1970; Series II; 2.25 linear feet
  This series contains Logan's personal and professional correspondence. It mostly includes incoming correspondence, but there are carbon copies of Logan's outgoin letters in many cases as well. The series is arranged chronologically. The bulk of the series focuses on Logan's education-related activities in Montana and Illinois, including the formation and maintenance of professional organizations and necessary exchanges with government officials to conduct business. For instance, he wrote the Missoula County Sheriff about illegal gambling in Arlee, Montana, that affected are schoolchildren. There are many long letters from editorial writer Quincy Sharpe Mills and from Carleton W. Washburne, a fellow educator and military man during World War II; he apparently carried out a long personal correspondence with both. There are many exchanges with politicians on both educational and other matters, including Joseph Dixon (on Roosevelt's Bull Moose campaign) Jeannette Rankin, Thomas J. Walsh, John M. Evans, and Mike Mansfield. He exchanged many letters with University of Montana--Missoula and Montana State University (Bozeman) faculty, and had a strong interest in the Louis Levine case at the University of Montana. He also continued his contact with the president and faculty at the University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill. The correspondence documents his active interests in religious and patriotic education, the cooperative movement, and democracy in schools. Post-retirement letters document his interest in promoting a Columbia Valley Authority (to be modeled on the Tennessee Valley Authority) that include more political correspondence;' he was also interested in water and irrigation issues on the Flathead. Some letters are also addressed to his wife, Frances, but the series does not include any replies from her.
  - 1906 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - 1912 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - January-July, 1913 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - August-September, 1913 (Box-folder 1/9)
  - October, 1913 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - November, 1913 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - December, 1913 (Box-folder 1/12)
  - 1914 (Box-folder 1/13)
  - 1915 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - 1916 (Box-folder 1/15)
  - 1917 (Box-folder 1/16)
  - 1918 (Box-folder 1/17)
  - 1919 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - 1920 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - January-June, 1921 (Box-folder 2/3)
  - July-December, 1921 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - January-June, 1922 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - July-December, 1922 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - January-June, 1923 (Box-folder 2/7)
  - July-December, 1923 (Box-folder 2/8)
  - January-June, 1924 (Box-folder 2/9)
  - July-December, 1924 (Box-folder 2/10)
  - 1925 (Box-folder 2/11)
  - January-June, 1926 (Box-folder 2/12)
  - pre-1926 (Box-folder 2/13)
  - 1927 (Box-folder 2/14)
  - 1928 (Box-folder 3/1)
  - 1929 (Box-folder 3/2)
  - 1930 (Box-folder 3/3)
  - 1931 (Box-folder 3/4)
  - 1932 (Box-folder 3/5)
  - 1933 (Box-folder 3/6)
  - 1934 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - 1935 (Box-folder 3/8)
  - 1936 (Box-folder 3/9)
  - 1937 (Box-folder 3/10)
  - 1938 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Simmons affair at the University of Montana--Missoula, 1938-1941 (Box-folder 3/12)
  - 1939 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Mission Range Credit Union, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 3/14)
  - 1940 (Box-folder 3/15)
  - 1941 (Box-folder 3/16)
  - January-June, 1942 (Box-folder 3/17)
  - July-December, 1942 (Box-folder 3/18)
  - Federal Communications Commission, NBC and CBS refusal to sell air time to co-op, 1942 (Box-folder 3/19)
  - Inland Steel, labor problem, 1942 (Box-folder 3/20)
  - 1943 (Box-folder 3/21)
  - 1944 (Box-folder 4/1)
  - 1945 (Box-folder 4/2)
  - January-June, 1946 (Box-folder 4/3)
  - July-December, 1946 (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Retirement, 1946 (Box-folder 4/5)
  - 1947 (Box-folder 4/6)
  - 1948 (Box-folder 4/7)
  - 1949 (Box-folder 4/8)
  - 1949 (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Flathead project, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 4/10)
  - Columbia Valley Authority, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 4/11)
  - Flathead Irrigation and Power Project, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 4/12)
  - 1950 (Box-folder 4/13)
  - 1951 (Box-folder 4/14)
  - 1952 (Box-folder 5/1)
  - 1954 (Box-folder 5/2)
  - 1955 (Box-folder 5/3)
  - 1956 (Box-folder 5/4)
  - 1957 (Box-folder 5/5)
  - 1958 (Box-folder 5/6)
  - 1959 (Box-folder 5/7)
  - 1960 (Box-folder 5/8)
  - 1961-1962 (Box-folder 5/9)
  - Co-ops and American Legion, 1962 (Box-folder 5/10)
  - 1963 (Box-folder 5/11)
  - Co-ops and American Legion, 1964 (Box-folder 5/12)
  - 1965 (Box-folder 5/13)
  - 1966-1967 (Box-folder 5/14)
  - 1968-1969 (Box-folder 5/15)
  - 1970 (Box-folder 5/16)
  - post-1926 and undated (Box-folder 5/17)
  - D.D. Cooper, 1948-1969 (Box-folder 5/18)
  - John F. Kennedy, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 5/19)
  - Logan's parents, 1910-1937 (Box-folder 5/20)
- Subject, 1926-1949; Series III; 2.5 linear feet
  This series contains materials collected by Logan for his educational and community activities. Most materials document his time at Skokie School, and include newsletters and other communications with faculty, parents, and students; materials from holidays and graduation; materials used to accompany slide lectures he did about the school; and materials from the student council and other leadership groups within the school. Materials in this series also document his deep and lifelong interest in right-wing extremism and its effect on eduction and academic freedom in Montana. There are many materials collected from the John Birch Society and similar groups, especially those who had active groups in Montana and Lake County. There are also a few materials related to taxation and its effect on educational opportunities in Montana.
  - Flooding of North Branch, Chicago River, 1936-1940 (Box-folder 5/21)
  - Academic freedom, undated (Box-folder 5/22)
  - Bicycle law, Skokie, 1941 (Box-folder 5/23)
  - Biology, Skokie School, course outline, undated (Box-folder 6/1)
  - Biology, Skokie School, questionnaire, undated (Box-folder 6/2)
  - Character education (Religious education), undated (Box-folder 6/3)
  - Children's letters, Skokie School, 1931-1945 (Box-folder 6/4)
  - Citizen's Commission of Education, Montana, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Civil rights: American Civil Liberties Union memo on the Red Scare, 1947; Malcolm Sharp (Box-folder 6/6)
  - By-Laws of Consolidated Dairies of Lake County, Inc., Ronan, Montana, 1944 (Box-folder 6/7)
  - Co-op milk route, North Shore Co-Op, undated (Box-folder 6/8)
  - Designing Education for the Future, 1967 (Box-folder 6/9)
  - Discipline, undated (Box-folder 6/10)
  - District #28 (Missoula County, Mont.), 1965 (Box-folder 6/11)
  - Joseph M. Dixon: sketch by K. Ross Toole and clippings, 1971 (Box-folder 6/12)
  - Writings on economic citizenship and the corporation, undated (Box-folder 6/13)
  - Writings on educational philosophy, "What are Schools For?", undated (Box-folder 6/14)
  - Board of Education [Skokie], 1946 (Box-folder 6/15)
  - Materials on extremism, clippings, John Birch Society, 1962-1969 (Box-folder 6/16)
  - Materials on right-wing extremism, 1961-1966 (Box-folder 6/17)
  - Correspondence on extremism, 1961-1967 (Box-folder 6/18)
  - Extremism, John Birch Society, 1962-1968 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Extremism, Congressional Record, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Extremism, Congressional Record, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 7/3)
  - Extremism, "A Report of the Public John Birch Society Meeting" held in Cut Bank, Montana, 1963 (Box-folder 7/4)
  - Extremism, Group Research Report, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Extremism, Lake County, Montana, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 7/6)
  - Extremism, letters to the editor, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Extremism, Montana, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 7/8)
  - Extremism, pro, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 7/9)
  - Extremism, pro, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Federal Union, 1941 (Box-folder 7/11)
  - Field studies (school field trips), undated (Box-folder 7/12)
  - Graduation program, Skokie School, 1946 (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Graduation ritual, Skokie School, 1940 (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Holiday festival (script), Skokie School, 1945 (Box-folder 8/3)
  - Homework, field studies, undated (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Individual instruction, 1945 (Box-folder 8/5)
  - Lecture trip, Cooperative League, 1946 (Box-folder 8/6)
  - Mexican trip, United States Department of Agriculture Extension Service, 1941 (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Mobile classroom (field studies), undated (Box-folder 8/8)
  - New citizens, undated (Box-folder 8/9)
  - Northern Illinois Superintendents Round Table, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 8/10)
  - Parliamentary practice aids, undated (Box-folder 8/11)
  - Principal's conference, 1941 (Box-folder 8/12)
  - Programs, meetings of education groups, 1931-1941 (Box-folder 8/13)
  - Readings for democracy, undated (Box-folder 8/14)
  - Religious education, school and religion, 1932 and undated (Box-folder 8/15)
  - Religious Education Association, minutes and bulletins, 1928-1935 (Box-folder 8/16)
  - Retirement party skit, 1946 (Box-folder 8/17)
  - Rochdale Institute, reports, 1941-1948 (Box-folder 8/18)
  - Salary schedules, Winnetka Public Schools, 1946-1948 (Box-folder 8/19)
  - Scripts, Skokie School, undated (Box-folder 8/20)
  - Service assembly, Skokie School, 1946 (Box-folder 8/21)
  - Shoplifting, property committee, Skokie School, 1945 (Box-folder 8/22)
  - Skokie School: Achievement of graduates, 1943-1948 (Box-folder 9/1)
  - Skokie School: Council and organizations, 1944 (Box-folder 9/2)
  - Skokie School: faculty bulletins, 1931-1935 (Box-folder 9/3)
  - Skokie School: faculty bulletins, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 9/4)
  - Skokie School: faculty bulletins, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 9/5)
  - Skokie School: faculty bulletins, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 9/6)
  - Skokie School: faculty bulletins, 1942 (Box-folder 9/7)
  - Skokie School: faculty bulletins, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 9/8)
  - Skokie School: Skokie School Law books, 1940-1945 (Box-folder 9/9)
  - Skokie School: Letters to parents and students, [1926]-1941 (Box-folder 9/10)
  - Skokie School: Letters to faculty, undated (Box-folder 9/11)
  - Skokie School: Organizations: Council, corporations, committees, 1940-1945 (Box-folder 9/12)
  - Skokie School: School council, 1935-1944 (Box-folder 9/13)
  - Skokie School: Junior High School: Organizations, advisors, 1931 and undated (Box-folder 10/1)
  - Skokie School: Organization sponsors, 1929 and undated (Box-folder 10/2)
  - Skokie X-Press, 1940-1946 (Box-folder 10/3)
  - Taxation, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 10/4)
  - Taxation: Equality of opportunity, undated (Box-folder 10/5)
  - Winnetka Teacher's Council Bulletin, 1938-1941 (Box-folder 10/6)
  - Carleton Washburne, by and about, 1928-1969 (Box-folder 10/7)
  - Winnetka schools, scripts to accompany slides, undated (Box-folder 10/8)
  - Winnetka schools, brochure, undated (Box-folder 10/9)
- Speeches and Writings, 1923-1968; Series IV; 1 linear foot
  This series contains Logan's published articles, speeches, and his autobiography (posthumously completed by Frances Logan), These Things Should Be. Published articles appeared in a variety of education publications and appear here in their published form. Speeches, almost all given in education settings, also include a talk given at a memorial service. The bulk of the series is the typed manuscript and one copy of These Things Should Be, which details his life and career and has an introduction and commentary added by Frances Logan.
  - 1923 (Box-folder 10/10)
  - 1926 (Box-folder 10/11)
  - 1928 (Box-folder 10/12)
  - 1929 (Box-folder 10/13)
  - 1932 (Box-folder 10/14)
  - 1933 (Box-folder 10/15)
  - 1934 (Box-folder 10/16)
  - 1940 (Box-folder 10/17)
  - 1941 (Box-folder 10/18)
  - 1942 (Box-folder 11/1)
  - 1943 (Box-folder 11/2)
  - Teachers' Council talk, 1944 (Box-folder 11/3)
  - 1945 (Box-folder 11/4)
  - 1946 (Box-folder 11/5)
  - 1947 (Box-folder 11/6)
  - 1952 (Box-folder 11/7)
  - 1954 (Box-folder 11/8)
  - Memorial service for Charles Stark, 1959 (Box-folder 11/9)
  - 1964 (Box-folder 11/10)
  - Resume of Montana Education Association presidency in 1925, 1964 (Box-folder 11/11)
  - 1968 (Box-folder 11/12)
  - Camp Douglas talk, undated (Box-folder 11/13)
  - Unpublished, undated (Box-folder 11/14)
  - Undated (after 1946) (Box-folder 11/15)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 11/16)
  - Articles in preparation, undated (Box-folder 11/17)
  - These Things Should Be, Frances Logan introduction and commentary, undated (Box-folder 16/1)
  - These Things Should Be, Part I, undated (Box-folder 16/2)
  - These Things Should Be, Part II, undated (Box-folder 16/3)
  - These Things Should Be, Part III, undated (Box-folder 16/4)
  - These Things Should Be, Part IV (Box-folder 16/5)
  - These Things Should Be, copy first half, undated (Box-folder 16/6)
  - These Things Should Be, copy second half, undated (Box-folder 16/7)
- Printed Materials and Scrapbooks, 1913-1970; Series V; 1.75 linear feet
  This series contains a variety of materials that document S. Rae Logan's career and interests. They include articles about him and Winnetka Schools by others, clippings on topics of interest to him, awards and certificates, and a two-volume scrapbook of mixed materials assembled for his sixtieth birthday in 1945.
  - Clippings, articles about S. Rae Logan and Winnetka Schools by others, 1931-1939 (Box-folder 11/18)
  - Clippings, articles about S. Rae Logan by others, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 11/19)
  - Clippings, articles about Skokie School by others, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 11/20)
  - Clippings, 1915 (Box-folder 11/21)
  - Clippings, Montana, 1913-1919 (Box-folder 11/22)
  - Clippings, Montana, 1919-1926 (Box-folder 11/23)
  - Clippings, 1948 (Box-folder 11/24)
  - Clippings, Co-ops, 1926 (Box-folder 11/25)
  - Clippings, Co-ops and American Legion, 1947 (Box-folder 11/26)
  - Clippings, District #28, Missoula County, Montana, 1919 (Box-folder 11/27)
  - Clippings, District #28, Missoula County, Montana, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 11/28)
  - Clippings, "Events S.R. Logan would have enjoyed knowing about", 1970 (Box-folder 11/29)
  - Clippings, Lake County (Montana) tax base, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 12/1)
  - Clippings, Missoulian (sale of), 1917 (Box-folder 12/2)
  - Clippings, Monopoly, 1939-1941 (Box-folder 12/3)
  - Clippings, Montana Power Company, 1969 (Box-folder 12/4)
  - Clippings, Senate race, 1924 (Box-folder 12/5)
  - Clippings, Skokie, 1926-1947 (Box-folder 12/6)
  - Clippings, University of Montana, 1968 (Box-folder 12/7)
  - Maps, Rutherford County, North Carolina; Winnetka, Illinois, undated (Box-folder 12/8)
  - [Collected articles, Montana Education Association materials, University of Montana teaching contract], 1924-1926 (Box-folder 12/9)
  - [Collected articles], 1950 (Box-folder 12/10)
  - [Pieces of letters and articles], undated (Box-folder 12/11)
  - Articles on co-ops, economics, 1932-1940 (Box-folder 12/12)
  - Articles on education, 1928-1941 (Box-folder 12/13)
  - Dedication of Clayton Washburne School, Winnetka, 1969 (Box-folder 12/14)
  - Articles and pamphlets, John Dewey, 1931 (Box-folder 12/15)
  - Articles, Flathead irrigation and power project, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 12/16)
  - Awards and certificates, 1956 (Box-folder 12/17)
  - Awards and certificates, 1916-1966 (Box-folder 13/1)
  - Educational Statesmanship, Volume 1, [1945] (Box-folder 15/1)
    "Compiled by his fellow-teachers on the occasion of his sixtieth birthday"
  - Educational Statesmanship, Volume 2, [1945] (Box-folder 15/2)
- Logan Ranch, 1931-1948; Series VI; 0.25 linear feet
  This series contains materials about the Logan ranch in St. Ignatius, Montana. It includes material on agricultural practices, buildings, cattle crops, and well drilling, but mostly concerns the leases and activities of tenants that rented the ranch while the Logans lived in Illinois.
  - Agricultural practices, 1937-1946 (Box-folder 13/2)
  - Building construction, 1935-1948 (Box-folder 13/3)
  - Cattle, 1939-1948 (Box-folder 13/4)
  - Crops, 1936-1945 (Box-folder 13/5)
  - Land, McVey and Spooner, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 13/6)
  - Land, Home 40, Upper 80, McPeck, English, 1931-1936 (Box-folder 13/7)
  - Land, Burchett L. Logan, 1931 (Box-folder 13/8)
  - Ranch, Stevensville, tenants, Lamoreux, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 13/9)
  - Ranch, tenants, Magini, 1939-1946 (Box-folder 13/10)
  - Ranch, tenants, McFadden, 1931-1934 (Box-folder 13/11)
  - Ranch, tenants, Tooker, 1931-1938 (Box-folder 13/12)
  - Ranch, tenants, Wining, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 13/13)
  - Well drilling, 1935 (Box-folder 13/14)
- Photographs, 1897-1968; Series VII; 0.5 linear feet
  This series contains primarily Logan family photographs and images of S. Rae Logan. They are mostly well-identified and include his ancestors, parents, siblings, early Montana and North Carolina scenes, his college days in Chapel Hill, the St. Ignatius, Montana, ranch and surrounding areas, Distict #28 and Winnetka Schools scenes, and images from Hardin, Montana.